Guide to the Doris Ulmann Photograph Collection ca. 1910-1934 PR 72
New-York Historical Society
- in long stretchy gown with short sleeves [Graham, Martha], 157463 (Item 1755)
- seated in long stretchy gown with long sleeves and hood [Graham, Martha], 157462 (Item 1756)
- crouching in long stretchy gown with long sleeves and hood [Graham, Martha], 157461 (Item 1757)
- standing in long sleeved, long light colored linen gown with frayed edges at hem and on sleeves [Graham, Martha], 157460 (Item 1758)
- salt and pepper hair, pulled back, parted in middle, light colored dress, holding straw band, in front of stone wall, 157459 (Item 1759)
- a girl in plaid dress, leaning on table with bowl of apples, a geranium, 157458 (Item 1760)
- in dark dress, pearls [Barnes, Margaret Ayers (1886-1967)], 157457 (Item 1761)
- soft straight, medium dark hair, flowered collar, 1919; 157456 (Item 1762)
- dark hair, in velvet gown or costume, 157455 (Item 1763)
- seated, medium dark, soft hair pulled back, long sleeved gown, 157454 (Item 1764)
- waved hair, velvet gown with white collar, with cigarette [Lewisohn, Mrs. Sam (Margaret Seligman)], 157453 (Item 1765)
  this image was also numbered 1764 and there was no image numbered 1765; # 768, 770-772, 790, 870, 1765, 2951 same subject
- silk crepe de chine blouse, pearls, dark waved hair, holding book, 157452 (Item 1766)
- in lace trimmed gown [Gish, Lillian], 157451 (Item 1767)
- adolescent girl, in dress with plaid top, white bow with buttons, short medium dark hair, plastic headband, with book, wristwatch, 157450 (Item 1768)
- girl with long dark hair, holding open book, seated, white dress, 157449 (Item 1769)
- in kimono robe, dark curly short hair, bang, 157448 (Item 1770)
- leaning on desk with pencil in hand, chin in other hand, salt and pepper hair pulled back, 157447 (Item 1771)
- dark short hair, slicked back, at table with pen and Japanese ink, 157446 (Item 1772)
- white hair, elderly, lace dress, pearls, 157445 (Item 1773)
  #1773, 1774 same subject
- white hair, elderly, dark dress with embroidery, lace collar and sleeves, at table with pencil and paper, 157444 (Item 1774)
- seated, long sleeved velvet gown with embroidery and beading, dark hair, stout [Hurst, Fannie, American author (1889-1968)], 157443 (Item 1775)
- dark hair and eyebrows, in short sleeved light colored blouse, seated with open book, 157442 (Item 1776)
- kneeling in grass outdoors in theatrical costume, very long elegant peacock cape, feathered headdress, 157441 (Item 1777)
- dark hair, ringlets, in white satin short sleeved town, long white gloves, 157440 (Item 1778)
- two women, one looks like a clerk, seated at desk with papers, woman standing has dark coat, hat, 157439 (Item 1779)
- large white collar, white hair, seated with book [Shaker Sister Adelaide of Mt. Lebanon, New York], 157438 (Item 1780)
  #872, 1780, 1785 same sub; on page 191, ca. 1925-26
- white hair, stout, in dark dress, 157437 (Item 1781)
- white curly hair, oval eyeglasses, elderly, dark dress and jacket, white high collared blouse, 157436 (Item 1782)
- seated, medium dark curly hair, short, floral print dress, 157435 (Item 1783)
- adolescent girl, chin length curly dark hair, long pearls, seated, 157434 (Item 1784)
- standing, large white collar, cloth bonnet [Shaker Sister Adelaide of Mt. Lebanon, New York], 157433 (Item 1785)
- seated, with open book, full white blouse with lace trim, dark skirt, salt and pepper hair pulled back, 1918; 157432 (Item 1786)
- wavy hair, medium dark, young, flowering tree in background, 157431 (Item 1787)
- straight, thick dark chin length hair, seated with cigarette, kimono-style jacket, 157430 (Item 1788)
- seated in dark jacket or blouse, at table with open book, pussy willow in vase, 157429 (Item 1789)
- short dark hair, dress with ruffled trim, with cigarette, 157428 (Item 1790)
- short straight hair, bangs, long notes, patterned woven or embroidered tunic [Forbes, Esther], 157427 (Item 1791)
- white hair, lace collar, old, knitting, 157426 (Item 1792)
- short hair, a little wavy, dark dress, collar and sleeves have interesting decorative trim, 157425 (Item 1793)
- in costume, headband, beaded belt, long straight dark hair, 157424 (Item 1794)
- in long white gauzy gown/costume, very long straight dark hair hangs loose, 157423 (Item 1795)
- very short dark hair, dark dress, square neck, 157422 (Item 1796)
- very long hair, headband, dark dress, watch, seated, 157421 (Item 1797)
- young, silk gauzy blouse, straight dark hair, parted on side, holding either a feather boa or a cat on lap, 157420 (Item 1798)
- medium dark hair, seated with book in wicker chair, 1916; 157419 (Item 1799)
- white hair, headband, pearls, lace tunic-dress, seated in studio chair with twisted spiral turn, 157418 (Item 1800)
- old, gray hair, maybe blind, polka dot blouse, seated working on a quilt, 157417 (Item 1801)
- wide brimmed straw hat, white apron, at laundry tub with wash board, outdoors, 157416 (Item 1802)
- old, heavy, seated on porch, crutch leaning against clapboard wall, patterned dress, round eyeglasses, medium dark thin hair, wedding band, 157415 (Item 1803)
- old, curly hair bunched up in a high hat, lace/cutwork blouse, safety pins as closures, 157414 (Item 1804)
- older, standing with broom handle or walking stick, patterned blouse, apron, outdoors on porch, 157413 (Item 1805)
- straight white hair pulled back, old, lips pursed, seated, print dress, polka dot scarf, 157412 (Item 1806)
  #1806-1809 same subject
- straight white hair pulled back, old, lips pursed, seated, print dress, polka dot scarf, shoulders up, head bowed, 157411 (Item 1807)
- straight white hair pulled back, old, lips pursed, seated, print dress, polka dot scarf, plant with frilly leaves, 157410 (Item 1808)
- straight white hair pulled back, old, lips pursed, seated, print dress, polka dot scarf, with knitting needle or pencil, 157409 (Item 1809)
- woman, checked blouse dark crocheted shawl, plaid apron, gray hair, seated, ivy-covered wall in background, 157408 (Item 1810)
- very wide-brimmed straw hat, standing with walking stick, shawl draped on arm, plaid blouse, apron, smiling, 157407 (Item 1811)
  # 1811-1814, 1819 same subject
- white fine hair, in small bun on top of head, plaid blouse, apron, smiling, seated, 157406 (Item 1812)
- very wide-brimmed straw hat, standing with walking stick, shawl draped on arm, plaid blouse, apron, smiling, 157405 (Item 1813)
- white fine hair, in small bun on top of head, plaid blouse, apron, smiling, seated, 157404 (Item 1814)
- old, seated, man's felt hat, patched tattered blouse with safety pin fasteners, checked apron, 157403 (Item 1815)
- young, penetrating gaze to camera, dark straight hair pulled back, floral patterned dress, pregnant?, standing in doorway, 157402 (Item 1816)
- seated, with man's felt hat, loose work blouse, dark skirt, smiling, in doorway, wedding band, 157401 (Item 1817)
- young, wide brimmed straw hat holding milk or cream can, in work pants with patch, work shirt, 157400 (Item 1818)
  subject in #1818 is in #1608
- old, thin straight hair in a bun, profile, seated, print dress with polka dot scarf, 157399 (Item 1819)
- Old, heavy, thin gray hair pulled back, flower print dress, checked apron, seated, 157398 (Item 1820)
- seated, light colored dress and apron, straight light colored hair pulled back, parted in middle, holding bible, 157397 (Item 1821)
- old, seated, woven wool shawl, several scarves wrapped around head, print blouse, 157396 (Item 1822)
- young, draped in white organza veil, light colored hair, 157395 (Item 1823)
- young, long dark hair falling onto chest, standing in the woods, holding a book, wearing a hat, long light colored dress, 157394 (Item 1824)
- standing in front of flowers (cosmos), hat, dress, necklace, white apron safety-pinned to dress, apron has floral embroidery, 157393 (Item 1825)
- two young, dark-skinned, plaid dresses, smiling, 157392 (Item 1826)
- two women, one younger leaning on tree trunk holding bundle, dark hair; older is seated holding tin bowl; both wearing matching checked aprons, 157391 (Item 1827)
  subject on left, younger woman, is also pictured plate 29 in Jacobs book, titled: "Monday, ca 1925-1929. Platinum print. Collection of the University of Kentucky Art Museum, No. 87.39.49
- dark straight hair, seated, pin-striped dress, 157390 (Item 1828)
- cloth bonnet, young, 157389 (Item 1829)
  #1829, 1830 same subject
- cloth bonnet, young, seated, 157388 (Item 1830)
  #1829, 1830 same subject; this print looks like an oil transfer print
- seated, dressed in man-style suit jacket, with tie, dark short hair, bracelet, smiling, 157387 (Item 1831)
  #1831-1840 same subject; looked up Radclyffe Hall (1880-1943), but other available images of Hall do not look like this subject
- seated, dressed in man-style suit jacket, with tie, dark very short hair, bracelet, in profile, holding cigarette, 157386 (Item 1832)
- seated, dressed in man-style suit jacket, with tie, dark very short hair, bracelet, 157385 (Item 1833)
- seated, dressed in man-style suit jacket, with tie, dark very short hair, bracelet, 157384 (Item 1834)
- seated, dressed in man-style suit jacket, skirt, with tie, dark very short hair, bracelet, 157383 (Item 1835)
- seated, dressed in man-style suit jacket, skirt, with tie, dark very short hair, bracelet, 157382 (Item 1836)
- seated, dressed in man-style suit jacket, skirt, with tie, dark very short hair, bracelet, 157381 (Item 1837)
- seated, dressed in man-style suit jacket, skirt, with tie, dark very short hair, bracelet, 157380 (Item 1838)
- seated, dressed in man-style suit jacket, skirt, with tie, dark very short hair, bracelet, 157379 (Item 1839)
- seated, dressed in man-style suit jacket, skirt, with tie, dark very short hair, bracelet, 157378 (Item 1840)
- posing standing shoulder to camera, hand on wall, other hand behind back, head down, dancer or actress, gauzy, puckered fabric gown, buttons from top of shoulder down sleeve to wrist, chin length curly fluffy hair, head band, 157377 (Item 1841)
  #1841, 1842 same subject
- posing standing facing camera, one arm raised and straight, other armed bent, dancer or actress, gauzy, puckered fabric gown, buttons from top of shoulder down sleeve to wrist, chin length curly fluffy hair, head band, 157376 (Item 1842)
- young, seated with ruler (or t-square?), dark dress with bow at neck, sleeves are pleated, dark hair, bangs, bun, 157375 (Item 1843)
- seated, suit, tie, vest, balding, ring, watch chain [Bloodyoor, Howland (see notes)], 157374 (Item 1844)
  #1844, 1851-1853 same subject; mat and mount missing, identification is hand written on back of photo
- standing by desk, microscope and slides, papers, suit, vest, tie, round eyeglasses [Bloodgood, Joseph Colt, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Surgery, Johns Hopkins Univ.], 157373 (Item 1845)
  #1845-1850, 1854, 1855, 2353, 2352 same subject, mat and mount missing
- seated by workbench, microscope and slides, papers, suit, vest, tie, round eyeglasses, surrounded by young men watching as he examines a bone (?) [Bloodgood, Joseph Colt, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Surgery, Johns Hopkins Univ.], 157372 (Item 1846)
  #1845-1850, 1854, 1855 same subject, mat and mount missing
- seated at workbench, microscope and slides, papers, suit, vest, tie, round eyeglasses, specimen of some kind on tray on bench [Bloodgood, Joseph Colt, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Surgery, Johns Hopkins Univ.], 157371 (Item 1847)
- seated at workbench, microscope and slides, papers, suit, vest, tie, round eyeglasses, holding specimen of some kind [Bloodgood, Joseph Colt, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Surgery, Johns Hopkins Univ.], 157370 (Item 1848)
- suit, vest, tie, round eyeglasses, holding specimen of some kind [Bloodgood, Joseph Colt, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Surgery, Johns Hopkins Univ.], 157369 (Item 1849)
- standing, suit, vest, tie, round eyeglasses [Bloodgood, Joseph Colt, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Surgery, Johns Hopkins Univ.], 157368 (Item 1850)
- standing by bench with beakers, holding glass tube instrument, lab coat, tie, balding, ring, [Bloodyoor, Howland (see notes)], 157367 (Item 1851)
  #1844, 1851-1853 same subject; mat and mount missing, identification is hand written on back of photo #1844
- standing by bench with beakers, holding glass tube instrument, lab coat, tie, balding, ring, [Bloodyoor, Howland (see notes)], 157366 (Item 1852)
- seated at desk, lab coat, tie, balding, ring, smiling [Bloodyoor, Howland (see notes)], 157365 (Item 1853)
- seated at desk, with book, suit, vest, tie, round eyeglasses [Bloodgood, Joseph Colt, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Surgery, Johns Hopkins Univ.], 157364 (Item 1854)
- seated at desk, with book, suit, vest, tie, round eyeglasses [Bloodgood, Joseph Colt, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Surgery, Johns Hopkins Univ.], 157363 (Item 1855)
- short medium dark straight hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, seated at desk or workbench with beakers, notebook, pen, suit, vest, tie [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU], 157362 (Item 1856)
  #1856-1865, 2390, 2391 same subject, subject is in JHU "A Book of Portraits" but not this image, mat and mount missing
- short medium dark straight hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, seated at desk or workbench with beakers, notebook, pen, suit, vest, tie [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU], 157361 (Item 1857)
- short medium dark straight hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, seated at desk or workbench with beakers, notebook, pen, suit, vest, tie, with cigarette [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU], 157360 (Item 1858)
  #1856-1865, 2390, 2391 same subject, mat and mount missing
- short medium dark straight hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, seated at desk or workbench with beakers, notebook, pen, suit, vest, tie [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU], 157359 (Item 1859)
- short medium dark straight hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, seated at desk or workbench with beakers, suit, vest, tie, with cigarette [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU], 157358 (Item 1860)
- short medium dark straight hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, seated at desk or workbench with beakers, notebook, pen, suit, vest, tie, with cigarette [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU], 157357 (Item 1861)
- short medium dark straight hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, seated at desk or workbench with beakers, suit, vest, tie, with cigarette [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU], 157356 (Item 1862)
- short medium dark straight hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, seated at desk or workbench with beakers, notebook, pen, suit, vest, tie [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU], 157355 (Item 1863)
- short medium dark straight hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, seated, suit, vest, tie [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU], 157354 (Item 1864)
- short medium dark straight hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, seated at desk or workbench with beakers, suit, vest, tie [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU], 157353 (Item 1865)
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, seated on couch with book, book case in background [Frankel, Dr. (see notes)], 157352 (Item 1866)
  #1866-1876 same subject; identification handwritten on back of photo # 1866, mat and mount missing
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, seated at desk with eyeglasses, books or pamphlets, 157351 (Item 1867)
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, seated with cigarette, 157350 (Item 1868)
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, seated at desk with eyeglasses, books or pamphlets, 157349 (Item 1869)
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, 157348 (Item 1870)
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, seated with cigarette, 157347 (Item 1871)
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, seated at desk with books or pamphlets, 157346 (Item 1872)
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, seated holding eyeglasses, bookcase in background, 157345 (Item 1873)
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, seated on couch with bookcase in background, 157344 (Item 1874)
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, with cigarette, 157343 (Item 1875)
- short, curly, wiry, salt and pepper hair, dark suit, vest, bow tie, seated on couch with big book, bookcase in background, 157342 (Item 1876)
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard, standing with sculpture of female nude [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157341 (Item 1877)
  #1877-1887 same subject; identification noted on Xerox; sculptor of Lincoln penny 1919; mat and mount missing
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard, standing with sculpture of female nude [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157340 (Item 1878)
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157339 (Item 1879)
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard, seated [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157338 (Item 1880)
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard, seated, medallion on easel [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157337 (Item 1881)
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard, seated, medallion on easel [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157336 (Item 1882)
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard, seated, working on medallion on easel [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157335 (Item 1883)
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard, seated, working on female bust [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157334 (Item 1884)
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard, seated, working on medallion on easel [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157333 (Item 1885)
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard, seated, working on medallion on easel [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157332 (Item 1886)
- balding, medium dark curly hair, mustache, beard, seated, working on medallion on easel [Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924, sculptor], 157331 (Item 1887)
- military uniform with decoration, balding, white mustache, 157330 (Item 1888)
- military uniform with decoration, balding, white mustache, 157329 (Item 1889)
  #1326, 1444, 1888, 1889, 1914-1918 same subject, mat and mount missing
- thinning light colored hair, mustache, dark suit, tie, seated, writing with pencil writing in book, 157328 (Item 1890)
  #1890, 1891, 1893 same subject; not in "A Portrait Gallery.. ."; mat and mount missing
- thinning light colored hair, mustache, dark suit, tie, 157327 (Item 1891)
- seated with newspaper (?), suit, tie, short, thick, white hair, mustache, dark skin, 157326 (Item 1892)
  #1892, 2321 same image; mat and mount missing
- thinning light colored hair, mustache, dark suit, tie, seated with book, 157325 (Item 1893)
- round eyeglasses, tie with horseshoe pin, with thick cardboard (?) record of some kind (?) [Tilney, Frederic, Professor of Neurology and Neuro-Anatomy, Columbia], 157324 (Item 1894)
- two older men with cameras, both in straw hats, suits, vests, bow ties, white hair, mustaches, seated in woods; one with pipe, must be photographers, 157323 (Item 1895)
  one of two subjects is in # 1896; mat and mount missing
- one of the two older men with cameras, both in straw hats, suits, vests, bow ties, white hair, mustaches, seated in woods; one with pipe, must be photographers, 157322 (Item 1896)
  subject is one of two men in # 1895; mat and mount missing
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence; standing with folder, lighted cigarette, 157321 (Item 1897)
  #1897-1910, 2221, 2280, 2315 same subject; mat and mount missing
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence, seated with book, 157320 (Item 1898)
  #1897-1910 same subject; mat and mount missing
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence, 157319 (Item 1899)
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence, 157318 (Item 1900)
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence, 157317 (Item 1901)
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence, 157316 (Item 1902)
- two men, one dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence; second is holding a stethoscope [Jaeger, Dr. Charles H., Ulmann's husband], 157315 (Item 1903)
  #1897-1910 first man same subject; mat and mount missing
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, in military uniform, 157314 (Item 1904)
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, in military uniform, 157313 (Item 1905)
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence, 157312 (Item 1906)
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence, 157311 (Item 1907)
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence, 157310 (Item 1908)
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence, 157309 (Item 1909)
- dark thinning hair, deep set dark eyes, prominent chin, double breasted suit, commanding presence, 157308 (Item 1910)
- very dark hair, smoothed back, young, dark mustache, double breasted light colored suit, tie, with cigarette, 157307 (Item 1911)
  mat and mount missing
- medium dark straight hair, young, round eyeglasses, seated, suit, tie, 157306 (Item 1912)
- very thick, straight dark hair, dark round eye glasses, dark mustache, dark suit, tie, vest, with pipe, 157305 (Item 1913)
- white mustache, military uniform, decorations, 157304 (Item 1914)
  #1326, 1444, 1888, 1889, 1914-1918, 2100-2108 same subject, mat and mount missing
- white mustache, military uniform, decorations, 157303 (Item 1915)
- white mustache, military uniform, decorations, 157302 (Item 1916)
- white mustache, military uniform, decorations, 157301 (Item 1917)
- white mustache, military uniform, decorations, 157300 (Item 1918)
- balding, white or gray hair, prominent nose, clean shaven, blazer, striped tie, 157299 (Item 1919)
  mat and mount missing; back of photo in Ulmann's handwriting: Doris Ulmann, 1000 Park Ave., N.Y. City
- stout, medium dark straight thinning hair, round eyeglasses, standing in white lab coat, tie, with metal instrument [Baer, William Stevenson, M.D., Associate Professor Clinical Orthopedic Surgery (see notes)], 157298 (Item 1920)
  #1920-1932, 2351 same subject; identified as "BAER" on back of #1920 and on Xerox copy; is subject in "JHU Portraits"
- stout, medium dark straight thinning hair, round eyeglasses, standing in white lab coat, tie, with metal instrument [Baer, William Stevenson, M.D., Associate Professor Clinical Orthopedic Surgery (see notes)], 157297 (Item 1921)
- stout, medium dark straight thinning hair, round eyeglasses, seated at desk with reading glasses, in dark striped suit, tie [Baer, William Stevenson, M.D., Associate Professor Clinical Orthopedic Surgery (see notes)], 157296 (Item 1922)